# CARLA ST JUSTE

Charlotte, NC 28217 · (704) 493-8553 · carlastjuste@gmail.com

## Full stack web developer

Versatile full stack web developer with over 7 years of experience in the Payment Card industry. Have strong ability to effectively manage multiple cross-functional projects concurrently. Have proven experience in implementing technical project on IBM I and DB2 running on Power Systems Servers. Experience with IBM I also include more than 2 years of security administration of the servers (Journaling, Service tools security, access control, backup and recovery, system values management...) and more than 5 years of developing applications with IBM SQL/PL.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Have experience with languages: T-SQL, IBM SQL/PL, IBM I Control Language
- Full stack development with: HTML, CSS, Node.js,
- Have experience with operating systems: IBM I, Windows, Linux.
- Have experience with IDE: IBM Data Studio, SQL Management Studio and Eclipse.
- Proficient in: MS Project, MS Visio, MS Excel, MS Power Point, MS World.

## **EXPERIENCE**

NOV 2020 – CURRENT

## **BILLING DESIGN ANALYST, CHARTER SPECTRUM**

- Works intimately with business owner/requestors or design architecture on understanding requirements and documenting requirements.
- Create SQL script in test and production to build high level design for complex configurations of the billers.
- Runs queries and pulls billing data to support analysis and billing design.
- Performs analysis on billing systems, billing data, and processes in order to determine the best billing design and solution.
- Designs solutions for MEC (Master Enterprise Catalog) to support the Gateway system.
- Works with Data Standards, requests data standard codes, and ensures we are following data standard guidelines.

#### MAR 2019 - MAR 2020

## IT PROJECT COORDINATOR, GROUPE SOGEBANK

- Planned and executed multi-departmental projects with internal and external stakeholders.
- Provided support to vendors and cross-functional teams with the implementation of new hardware or software.
- Created, maintained and monitored the project plans and schedules.
- Provided project activity guidance to team members including activity start/finish dates and potential issues/opportunities arising related to activity progression.
- Helped with the documentation of each phase of the project, as well as making summary reports that will be presented to the General Manager or the Board members.

## **Key Achievements:**

• EMV 3-D Secure implementation for Sogebank credit cards: Led this project to a successful conclusion. This implementation allowed the bank to add an additional security layer for the card not present transactions by validating a one-time password previously sent to the cardholder. As a result, the bank considerably reduced the fraud for the online transactions, was able to cut some chargeback fees and improved its authorizations rate.

#### FEB 2016 - FEB 2019

## **OPERATIONS MANAGER, GROUPE SOGEBANK**

- Designed and implemented operational policies and procedures for the credit cards, prepaid cards and merchant acquiring activities.
- Interfaced with Sogebank IT department, Central Bank, software vendors, Mastercard, Visa to resolve any technical issues related to the credit card, prepaid and merchant system, following up with resolution of problems to ensure timely response.
- Participated in project task force to represent the department.
- Oversaw any enhancement of equipment such as POS, credit card printers, card personalization devices, Visa and Mastercard Simulators, test tools (Collis, Barnes).
- Worked with the software development team to implement data strategies, build data flows and develop conceptual data models for the applications that interact with the Transaction Management System database.
- Enabled effective decision-making by retrieving and aggregating data from multiple, sometimes isolated, data sources and compiling it into a digestible and actionable format.

### **Key Achievements:**

- National Payment Processing Switch: Led the technical aspect of this project that allow the interconnection of the Central Bank payment processing switch to the Sogebank switching system. Consequently, as an acquirer Sogebank was able to accept and process transactions from all the private label debit cards issue by most financial institutions in Haiti. As a card issuer, Sogebank was able to authorize OFF-US transactions for its private label ATM cards.
- Mastercard Automatic Billing Updater: An application developed and deployed on AS400\IBM I that creates a daily file containing Sogecarte's customers account information update according to the requirements of Mastercard.
- Credit Card portfolio Conversion from USD to HTG: Created on AS400\IBM I the conversion scripts for the credit cards with a negative balance.
- World Cup Raffle application: Developed an application that subsequently drawn at random 10 winner that base on their transaction during a specific period of time. The more credit card transaction you have during that define period the more chance you have to win a prize.

#### AUG 2013 - JAN 2016

## IT SECURITY ANALYST, GROUPE SOGEBANK

- Planned and implemented security for the Core Banking and the Card Management System.
- Managed and Monitored security access of the financial applications.
- Maintained high security-standard on the IBM I servers by fixing vulnerabilities and applying critical enhancements.
- Perform investigation on request.

# **EDUCATION**

**JUL 2012** 

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING** 

STATE UNIVERSITY OF HAITI

# TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

- IBM I System Administration Enskill
- RPG programming Enskill
- IBM I Security Fundamentals Enskill
- Control Language Programming Enskill
- Developing SQL Databases (Exam 70-761 scheduled to pass on September 25<sup>th</sup> 2020)— Microsoft
- Querying Data with Transact SQL (Exam 70-761 passed) Microsoft
- Fintech: Foundation, Payments and Regulations University of Pennsylvania on Coursera
- Mastercard Simulator Mastercard Academy